An obsession with creativity and Kubrick
Filmworker is a documentary film directed by Tony Zierra.
The story of Leon Vitali, who surrendered his promising acting career
to become Stanley Kubrick's devoted right-hand man.
Self, played by Leon Vitali.
Self, played by Ryan O'Neal.
Self, played by Danny Lloyd.
Self, played by Matthew Modine.
Self, played by R. Lee Ermey.
Self, played by Stellan Skarsgård.
Filmworker is a 2017 American documentary film directed by Tony Zierra about Leon Vitali, a successful British actor who, after playing the role of
Lord Bullingdon in the Stanley Kubrick-directed Barry Lyndon, gave up his acting career to work for decades as Kubrick’s assistant.
Filmworker premiered at the 2017 Cannes Film Festival on May 19 and was
nominated for the L'Œil d'or, le prix du documentaire – Cannes.
The film explores themes of interview, behind the
scenes, filmmaking, dedication.